RG 004:027, Clinton Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Inventory of Records
1862-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate (Clinton District)
33.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1862-1967; Probate files, 1903-1975.
RG004_027
2011-057 and 2011-058
Historical Note
Clinton, Middlesex County, Town established in May 1838, Parent Town: Killingworth
The Clinton Probate District was constituted July 5, 1862 from the Killingworth Probate District. The Clinton Probate District merged with the Deep River, Essex, Haddam, Killingworth, Lyme, Old Saybrook, Saybrook, and Westbrook Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Saybrook Probate District. The Saybrook Probate District serves the municipalities of Chester, Clinton, Deep River, Essex, Haddam, Killingworth, Lyme, Old Saybrook, and Westbrook.
Town of Clinton, Probate District chronology:
May 1838 - July 4, 1862, Killingworth District
July 5, 1862 - January 4, 2011, Clinton District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Saybrook District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes, 1-6, 9-15, 1862-1967. Volumes 7 and 8 were not transferred to the State Archives and their location is not known. Contact probate court for to access record books after Volume 15. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1903-1975. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 15. Volumes 7 and 8 are not present.
Probate files are arranged as received from the probate court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-058.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Clinton
Places:
Clinton (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-057, Record books, 1862-1967; and Accession 2011-058, Probate files, 1903-1975, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 2, 3, 5, 7, 9, 1862-1915, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2011-057 and probate files in accession 2011-058 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 29, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1862-1967; 7.5 cubic feet (13 volumes); 2011-057
  - Orders and decrees, 1862-1880 (Box 1)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1862-1879, 1888 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1879-1898 (Volume 3)
  - Orders and decrees, 1880-1892 (Box 4)
  - Wills, 1879-1926 (Box 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1892-1904 (Box 6)
  - Records, 1905-1916 (Volume 9)
  - Orders and decrees, 1916-1929 (Box 10)
  - Records, 1916-1929 (Box 11)
  - Wills, 1916-1967 (Box 12)
  - Records, 1929-1933 (Box 13)
  - Records, 1932-1939 (Box 14)
  - Records, 1939-1942 (Box 15)
- Probate Files, 1903-1975; 16 cubic feet; 2011-058
  - Probate files, 1903-1975 (Box 1-16)